

MOHAMED ABD ELMONEM SHOSHA

TECHNICAL OFFICE ENGINEER

EMAIL: Mohamed.shosha2020@gmail.com

Mobile: 01143401739

PROFILE

Civil engineer with 5 years working experience in constructions field, High qualified technical office engineer in shop drawings, quantity surveying, and invoices.

Areas of experience covering: -

• Residential Buildings

Public Buildings

• Touristic Buildings

Infrastructures

WORK EXPERIENCES

-Alexandria Construction Company ACC - Talat Moustafa Group • Egypt

-FOUR SEASONS HOTEL-LUXOR

MAY, 2021 to present

- Review and coordinate design drawing with architectures, MEP.
- Review and Study dewatering process (soil report, technical report, commercial offers, etc.)
- Review and Study shoring system and prepare method statement.

-FOUR SEASONS RESORT-SHARM EL SHIKH

Owner: Talat Moustafa Group, Main consultants: Shaker Consultancy Group SCG

Project Management: Dar El Handsa Project Value: More than 1 Billion LE

1) - FOUR SEASONS UTILITY ISLAND

October, 2019 to May, 2021

- Prepare shop drawings and as-built drawings, and ensure documentations and records in use are reviewed and approved.
- Review and coordinate design drawing with architectures, MEP and underground utilities.
- Review and coordinate shop drawing with architectures, MEP.
- Prepare shop drawings for a new 390 m² single story, cast-in-place reinforced concrete **Diesel Generator Building**.
- Prepare shop drawings for a new 1125 m² single story, cast-in-place reinforced concrete **Underground Tanks and Chiller/Boiler Building.**
- Prepare shop drawings for a new 450 m² single story expansion to the existing **Desalination Plant Building**.
- Prepare shop drawings for a new 450 m² single story, cast-in-place reinforced concrete **Sewage Treatment Plant Building.**
- Study and prepare request for information (RFI).

2) -FOUR SEASONS EXTENSION RESORT

January, 2018 to October, 2019

- Prepare shop drawings and as-built drawings, and ensure documentations and records in use are reviewed and approved.
- Prepare shop drawings for swimming pools, SPA, water features and ensure full coordination with MEP drawings.
- Ensure the distribution of the shop drawings with the latest revision.
- Study and prepare request for information (RFI).
- Prepare strengthening details for redesign buildings.

-Jedar Consulting Engineers Office • Egypt

July, 2016 to November, 2016

- Manage site work to install finishing items (ceramic, plastering, pointingetc).
- Ensure site work performed according to quality standard and project specifications.
- Review contractors surveying sheets and invoices.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Degree of Civil Engineering, May, 2016

Grade: Good, excellent graduation project MANSOURA UNIVERSITY | EGYPT

ENGINEERING TRAINING

• The Arab Contractors- Manoura City- Site Engineer (28, June, 2015 to 30 July 2015)

SOFTWARE ASSISTANT PROGRAMS

- AutoCAD
- Revit Structure
- Primavera p6
- SAP 2000
- Safe
- Etabs
- CSI Column
- MS Office (Word, Excel, Power point, etc.)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Arabic: Native language

• English: Good writing. reading and speaking

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Nationality: Egyptian

Date of Birth: January, 1, 1993

Marital status: Married